in the evening in Moscow it begins, that's true,
к вечеру в Москве начинается вот правда
I'm a very energetically
вот я очень энергетически такой вот
sensitive person, I can even hear
человек чувствительный я даже слышу как
the sockets ringing, my husband was born in
розетки вот звенят у меня муж родился в
Moscow, they ask, Do you hear the
Москве спрашивают Ты слышишь как звенят
sockets ringing, he's like, no, that's it, They don't
розетки он такой нет такой Они же бз
do it, he's like, No, I don't hear it
делают он такой Нет я не слышу зт я
I hear too
слышу тоже
I hear I hear I also hear there is a sound if you
слышу я слышу Я тоже слышу там звук если
listen so as not to hear the cars
прислушаться вот чтобы не слышать машины
and so on you can hear the sound coming from the sockets
и так дальше слышно идёт от розеток звук
Hello, you have a nice smile,
Здравствуйте у вас симпатичная улыбка
you have a very kind look and in general your face
очень у Вас добрый взгляд и вообще лицо
in general this is a
в общем это
deceptive impression you think yes then
обманчивое впечатление думаете да тогда
Mutually I enter into  trust and then I stand
Взаимно я вхожу в доверие а потом стою
angry It happens but everything Mutually depends on the child
злым Бывает такое но всё Взаимно от дете
and on the people I am from the city of
го от людей зависит Я из города
Khmelnitsky Ukraine And
Хмельницкий Украина А вы
where are you from I am from Moscow at the moment and before
откуда Я с Москвы в данный момент а до
this moment where were you and before that I
данного момента где были а до этого я
was in
была в
Mariel Are you a Mari from Yezh
Мариэл Вы марийка из еш
Korly Yes you  you know my father is a Mari from
корлы Да вы знаете у меня отец мариец из
school ro Well, like there was some village near the school
школы ро Ну типа рядом с школой какое-то
he was from there What are you
село деревня была он оттуда родом Да вы
talking about, I'm half
что здоро я наполовину
Maria I am also half and my mother is
Марии Я тоже наполовину а у меня мама
Udmurt and I am and who is your second one
удмуртка у меня а у вас кто второй у
I am Tatar and my mother is Udmurt and my father is
меня татарин А у меня мама удмуртка отец
Mari God, just a true Fino Highlander
мариец Боже прямо а истинный фино Горец
Yes I am a Fino Highlander Yes I say so I am a Fino
Да я фино Горец Да я так и говорю я фино
Ugr Great sometimes they say that  that this
угр Здорово когда-то говорят то что эта
nation was the strongest it
нация была самой сильной она
occupied In power in general by blood
зани Во власти вообще по крови
by body Yes very strong roots especially
по телу Да очень сильные корни особенно
in fortune telling they say such people They are forest
в гаданиях говорят такие люди Они лесные
people forest hunters forest dwellers they
люди лесные охотники лесные жители им не
lack nature I still nave also
хватает природы Я до сих пор наве тоже
lack nature
не хватает природа
here I go out We have  The thing is that my
вот я выхожу У нас Дело в том что меня
father took me out here in Ukraine, even
отец выводил тут в Украине даже в
found a birch grove and we watered the fire there, in
находил берёзовую рощу и мы там костёр
short, we did rituals, so my
полили короче обряды делали вот меня
mother Do you know what makes me do,
мама Знаете что заставляет делать
jump over a fire where they burn, for example,
прыгать через костёр где горят например
mazhe
маже
velk,
вельк
a feeling of something like that It’s probably hard for you,
ощущение что-то такое Вам Тяжело
yes, there in Ukraine  it's very
наверное да там на Украине сейчас очень
hard now it's very hard it's very hard Roche that
тяжело очень тяжело очень тяжело Рош что
you at least have light now I can't
у вас хотя бы сейчас свет есть Я не
imagine I was already thinking that I
представляю я уже думала то что мне
probably also need to buy some I do
наверное тоже нужно купить какую-нибудь
n't know some kind of  it's called
не знаю какую-то как она называется
a bourgeois stove because even now so
буржуйку потому что и сейчас так много
much of this negative stuff is happening. The thing
всего происходит такого негатив ва Дело
is that now, look, I saw that
в том что сейчас смотрите я видел что
your Leningrad region has already been bombed
уже вашу Ленинградскую область бомбили
more than
так не
once. The thing is that here, yes, look,
раз у нас тут дело в том что да Смотрите
there's a military plant not far from me in Ukraine
тут недалеко от меня в Украине военный
and they're making
завод и делают вот эти беспилотники как
I have a friend who works on these drones,
раз у меня знакомый работает на нём
he says: These were sent to the
говорит Вот это отправляли на
Leningrad region to you and to Ust-
Ленинградскую область к вам да в Усть
Uluk, experimental samples, everything
улук экспериментальные образцы всё
flew fine, now they are already making a
нормально долетела теперь делают уже
batch of 400 of these drones, there are more being
партия 400 этих беспилотников есть и ещё
made, and now they will launch them, like, this is
делают Да теперь будут пускать ка ка это
all ours  they are doing now I will tell you 5 minutes
всё наше же творят сейчас сказам 5 минут
please okay good now Therefore it is
пожалуйста окей хорошо сейчас Поэтому
better to buy for yourself as you know here
лучше покупайте себе так как знаете вот
you looked at the Times magazine Yes And have you seen
вы смотрели журнал Times Да А вы видели
Here is the new cover of 2005 it is
Вот это новая обложка 2005 году она
so interesting It basically
такая интересная Она же в принципе
consists of David true here is
состоит из Давида правда вот там вот вот
this here is what in  It happened in Anapa, then
это вот что в Анапе случилось потом
it turns out to be Los Angeles, then to
там получается лос-анджелес потом на
China, there in China, there was immediately, like,
Китай вот там в Китае сразу типа
an infection. Although people say, Yes, we
заражение Хотя люди говорят Да у нас
don’t have everything at all, everything is fine, and here we are
вообще нет всё прекрасно и вот и нами
simply being manipulated by people, right?  we are
просто манипулируют люди же вот мы же
all simple people, what can we
все люди простые что мы можем
do, we do what we can, of course, we insert
сделать мы как можем конечно вставляем
Of course, we must go and insert into
Конечно Мы должны ходить вставлять в
organizations to hammer them for our own
организаци в долбить их по своим
popular reasons Yes, for example, like a
народным причинам Да например как скан
passport scan, there are all these different requirements, the
паспорта там эти всякие требования
transition to electronic ones, well, I don’t
переход там на электронные там ну не
know what you
знаю как вы
think, against digital  systems I have
думаете против цифровой системы у меня
many children and I, for example, do not want to
много детей и Я например не желаю их
include them in any unknown to me databases
включать в всякие неизвестные мне базы
that It is not known what else in the
которые Неизвестно что ещё на мотря в
future they are in that Look They
будущем они ло в том что Смотрите Они
want to give everyone a digital code and through a
хотят каждому при цифровой код и через
digital code control everyone I
цифровой код контролировать всех Я же
was also in Auschwitz  I had an
была тоже в Освенциме у меня вот там
uncle in Auschwitz and in the end they
дядя в аушвице был да и всех в итоге
killed everyone and what happened was the
всех погубили и что Получилось же был
Yurlin trial where it is not allowed It is not allowed like that
юрлинский процесс где Нельзя Нельзя так
And now look at you, you have this, you
А сейчас смотрите у вас вот это у вас
have also made codes there SNILS or something like that Yes,
тоже сделали коды там СНИЛС или как Да у
you have Yes, of course, this is already with everyone  code and
вас Да конечно это уже с каждому коду и
without the code you can't do anything
без кода вы ничего не сможете сделать
already everything Initially you know how it was
уже всё Изначально знаете как было
initially sl it was for employers
изначально сл он был для работодателей
That is, you could get it after 18 years
То бишь ты его мог получить после 18 лет
when you were already trying to work so that
когда ты уже стремился потрудиться чтобы
you this accrued taxes yes yours
ты этот начислял налоги да твой
employer and as a result now a child
работодатель а в итоге сейчас ребёнок
is born and automatically without a
рождается и ему уже автоматом без
request without an application it is
запроса без заявления
also credited. For example, I
начисляется также Вот я например ребёнка
didn’t register my child anywhere.
нигде не регистрировалась
What is the name of the POM? And that is, they
Как называется помс Да и то бишь они за
decided for me. Where will my child be? What
меня решили Где мой ребнок будет В какой
insurance company will it be in? They decided for me and there
страховой будет за меня решили а там у
we have  in the legislation it is written either by
нас в законодательстве написано либо по
parents or some other
родителям либо ещё какой-то другой
option in short well such an option that
вариант короче ну такой вариант кото
how many children do you have three and in the end they
сколько у вас детей трое и в итоге вот
registered the child there like Where are the parents
записали ребёнка там типа Где родители
He is in a completely different organization That is
Он вообще в другой организации То бишь
this MS decided for That is they are already who
этот МС решил за на То бишь они уже кем
work By the way I work in the audit field I
работаете Кстати я в аудиторской сфере
used to work now I'm on maternity leave and
Раньше работала сейчас я в декрете и
for some reason someone decided something for me
почему-то за меня кто-то что-то решил
Why for me to more look what
Почему за меня к больше смотрите что что
they did they made everyone so that
они сделали они всем сделали так чтобы
people opened cards in the bank here
люди открывали в банке карточки вот у
you have cards  Yes, I have an account in the bank on the
вас есть карточки Да счёт име в банке на
card that there are numbers. Code, yes, you understand
карточке что есть цифры Код да понимаете
and you have this code privately for you,
и вы этот код приват вам
you become a slave of the bank. When you signed,
вы стате рабом банка Когда вы подписали
I understand this, but I also understand that
я это понимаю но также понимаю то что у
I initially had it in Sberbank at my
меня изначально был в Сбербанке по моему
birth, when it was not Sberbank but
рождению когда был не Сбербанк а была
Savings bank of the Soviet Union and I had
Сберкасса Советского Союза и у меня был
an account but it turns out that for all of us they
счёт а получается на всех нам всего
didn't give us a lot of things By the way, do you have them?
много чего не додали Кстати а у вас У
You are also developing this European
вас тоже развивают Вот это Европейское
5G Yes, they are
5G Да вышки
installing towers, by the way, it has a very strong effect, it has a very
ставят кстати очень сильно влияет очень
strong effect. I bought a card for myself, I
сильно влияет я себе купила карту я её
gave it to my brother when I had  my brother had
брату подарила когда у меня у брата был
a heart attack I gave him these cards
инфаркт я ему подарила вот эти вот карты
as a gift they are very strong in the evening
как раз-таки они очень сильно вечером
depression begins I also I don't
начинается депрессия Я к тому же я не
know how you feel about
знаю как вы относитесь к
mushrooms For example me I am such a person
грибам Например я Я вообще такой человек
I am very natural For example I
я очень природный Вот я например
use it because  true,
употребляю потому что вот правда вот
you know, consciousness is starting to change,
знаете сознание меняется начинается у
I have a friend like that from
меня есть знакомый такой из
Yekaterinburg, he also does
Екатеринбурга тоже он
this, I bought some, by the way, they
этим я купила такие кстати вот на меня
affect me more than I do, I drink, I drink, I drink already
влияют больше чем я вот пью пью пью уже
in capsules, I don’t know, he’s got fives for
в капсулах там не знаю по пятёрки он у
me at all. But he at least tells me
меня вообще А вот он мне хотя бы к
in the evening in Moscow it begins here is true
вечеру в Москве начинается вот правда
here I am a very energetically
вот я очень энергетически такой вот
sensitive person I can even hear how
человек чувствительны я даже слышу как
the sockets ring my husband was born in
розетки вот звенят у меня муж родился в
Moscow asks do you hear how the
Москве спрашивает ты слышишь как звенят
sockets ring he is like no like that They do it
розетки он такой нет такой Они же делают
he is like No I don't hear  zvi I
он такой Нет я не слышу зви я слышу
hear I hear I hear I also hear the sound there if you
слышу я слышу Я тоже слышу там звук если
listen so as not to hear the cars
прислушаться вот чтобы не слышать машины
so further you can hear the sound coming from the sockets
так дальше слышно идёт от розеток звук
yes yes And when I turn on the
да да А когда я по всей квартире включаю
wi-fi and this throughout the apartment at least more or less
и wi-fi и этот меня хотя бы более-менее
muffle me but I live  in an apartment
приглуши но я живу в многоквартирном
building and there, as if the neighbors have
доме и там уже как бы у соседей везде
Wi-Fi everywhere, I think they came up with all this, it would have been
wi-fi везде Я думаю это всё придумали
possible to make one station for the
можно же было сделать одну станцию на
entire entrance and for it to provide for everyone,
весь подъезд и чтобы она всех обеспечила
it would have been more economical, firstly, yes, it would
это было бы экономнее во-первых да это
have been more harmless, now you turn it on,
было бы более безвредно сейчас включаешь
Yes  now you turn on 20 wi-fi from the
Да сейчас включаешь там 20 вай-фае от
neighbors and all this wi-fi passes through us
соседей и оно ж всё этот wi-fi через нас
through us the brain to our electricity
проходит через нас мозг на наше электро
is interesting so I talked to the neighbor and
са интересное вот я с соседкой
asked if you could at least
разговаривала попросила можешь хотя бы
turn off the wi-fi for 2-3 days before the breakdown
на 2-3 дня вот перед слом выключить
I  I want to say to understand what is happening to me
wi-fi Я хочу говорю понять что со мной
maybe it seems true to me
происходит может быть мне это правда
I want to just say
кажется я хочу просто говорю
to experiment
поэкспериментировать
she is like No my husband plays Yes know
она такая Нет у меня муж играет Да позна
Well you know people like that they are
Ну вот люди-то знаете такие типа вот они
not  understand what's going on around them they are
не понимают что вокруг происходит они
like that I live for today It's important to me
такие Я живу сегодняшним днём Мне важно
that my husband comes home from work he earned
чтобы Муж пришёл с работы он заработала
money so that I have something to eat the children
денежку чтобы у меня было пожрать детей
What to feed them and so that they are clean,
Чем Чем накормить и чтобы они были чисты
well-fed and vaccinated there are more and more children ugh
сытые и привитые всё детей больше фу
children for some reason children because
детей почему-то детей потому что может
maybe  people True, all such small
быть люди Правда все такие маленькие
children you know, no matter how
дети знаете независимо от того сколько
old they are, they end up getting vaccinated You too
им лет они в итоге ма прививки Вы тоже
Let me clarify, you didn't vaccinate your children like that
Уточняю прививки вы детям не делали так
Yes, I don't either Yes, I have I have, like,
Да я тоже не делаю Да у меня есть у меня
several children, one is fully
как бы Несколько детей одна полностью
vaccinated, the second is partially vaccinated And the third is completely
привита второй частично А третья вообще
not vaccinated and the third she is the healthiest the
не привита и третья она Самая здоровая
most powerful the most like this right and
самая мощная самая такая вот прямо а
products you buy products from the supermarket
продукты вы продукты из супермаркета
or grow them yourself no from the
покупаете Или выращиваете сами нет из
village I bring I bring from the village my
деревни привожу привожу из деревни у
aunt keeps milk and sour cream and
меня там тётя держит молоко и сметану и
cottage cheese there potatoes If you are from Mari A you live in
творог карто Если вы из Мари А живёте в
Moscow or  in St. Petersburg how Where is your
Москве или в Питере как Где у вас
village I bring I order in advance they
деревня я привожу я заранее заказываю
bring me big boxes of eggs
мне привозят большие коробки яйца
they bring everything they bring I
привозят всё привозят я заранее
order a taxi in advance as if I already have
заказываю такси как бы у меня тут уже
my own system here yes  it comes out very expensive but
своя система да выходит очень дорого но
I try for myself and for the children for
я для себя и для детей стараюсь для
my husband in general for if you or the
своего мужа вообще для вот если вы или
children get sick with a fever how do you
дети заболели температура как
treat turpentine baths firstly
лечитесь скипидарные ванны во-первых
if
если
ka as
ка как
if they are sold in pharmacies So we
бы продаются в аптеках Так что е
brew it and drink if there is a cough if there is a cough
завариваем пьём если кашель если кашель
for example plantain also helps  but
например также помогает подорожник но
plantains and everything else how much of this
подорожники и всё оста с сколько этого
How much do you need to drink per day listen you know
Сколько надо в день пить слушайте знаете
I do it by eye by eye I brew it and it's
я делаю на глаз на глаз завариваю и
enough for the kids literally even I give it to them once
детям хватает буквально даже один раз им
a day and it's enough for them that's also
даю в сутки и им хватает вот также
Plantain My mother does it That's
Подорожник У меня мама занимается Вот
exactly how I collect it  all sorts of plants
как раз-таки вот сбором всяких растений
she dries them ferments some
она их высушивает ферменти ет некоторые
When necessary you have this knowledge from Ma all
Когда необходимо ва эти знания от Ма все
yes I understand it was passed on I just
да я так понимаю передались я просто
listen to my mother I don't have any special knowledge but
слушаю маму У меня нет особых знаний но
I listen to my mother My mother is like that she
я слушаю маму У меня мама такая вот она
collects herbs and so on at the right time
по сбору трав и так далее в нужное время
in  some lunar day This is already kind of
в какой-то лунный день Это уже как бы
her
пока её
prerogative And where do you collect that
прерогатива А где вы собираете что ещё
again I
раз я его
buy it from us I don’t know it I think
покупаю у нас его не знаю Мне кажется у
we don’t have
нас его нет
it My mother also collects and  dries
намер У меня мама тоже собирает и сушит
We have a special
У нас есть специально имеется сушилка
multi-storey dryer
такая многоэтажная
Well,
Да ну
there should also be a
для там тоже должна быть как я помню
certain drying temperature as I remember and you
определённая температура сушки а иван
don't collect Ivan tea we
чай не собираете
collect how much Ivan tea do you have a
собираем сколько у вас
lot of Ivan tea a lot of different
иванча очень много очень много разных
years the
годов у
room the hall is littered with Ivan tea while it is
комната зала завалена иван чаем пока она
then we
потом мы её
shift it  in
перекладываем в
the oven Well, in general, we do it with our hands and in the oven and in
печку Ну в общем мы и руками и в печку и
this way and with Skim, we generally
таким образом и Ским мы вообще как
sit like Cubans and we can say we do it
кубинцы сидим и можно сказать делаем
cool and interestingly yes And for example, well
прикольно интересно да А хорошо например
And if a child has Well, sihon tea, it
А если у ребёнка Ну сихон чай он Он
smells like an apple yes And if a child is very
пахнет яблоком да А если ребёнок сильно
sick, you  are you taking him to the hospital or something
заболел вы его везёте там в больниц или
like that? By the way, you know there was such a case,
как А кстати знаете был такой случай вот
recently my child came from Georgia from the
недавно у меня ребнок приехал с Грузии с
Black Sea and he got very sick and
Чёрного моря и он очень сильно заболел и
went to the hospital. We went because there was already
в больницу Пошли потому что уже была
such hysteria, we went, and in the end the
такая истерика пошли пошли и в итоге
doctor didn’t even prescribe blood tests
Врач даже анализы крови не назначил
at all.  did nothing absolutely
вообще ничего не сделал совсем абсолютно
nothing I entrusted this matter to my husband my husband as
ничего я это дело доверила мужу муж как
always
всегда
and I cured him with my mother
и я вылечила его с мамой
Here and with plantain and as it
Вот и подорожником и как
turned out in fact my child
оказалось по факту у меня ребёнок
almost every  2 months and it seems to me He
каждого почти 2 месяца и мне кажется Он
brought
привёз
whooping cough Yeah and hospitals are like that if it
коклюш Угу а больницы они такие если бы
seems to me the doctor had guessed if they had
мне кажется врач догадался если бы
identified it by tests there would have been 100%
выявили по анализам там было бы уже 100%
then maybe the hospital would have
то больницу может быть бы на карантин
been quarantined and so on they are most likely
поставили и так далее они скорее всего
afraid of this
этого боятся
I understand and here  do you have children Well, I'm
понял вот а у вас имеются дети Ну я пока
just planning to have a family I The thing is
только собираюсь семю завести я Дело в
that I'm looking for a woman who also Well The thing is
том что ищу женщину которая тоже Ну Дело
that I'm very glad that I met
в том что я вот очень рад что встретил
you with such knowledge you know now
вас вот с такими знаниями знаете сейчас
modern girls they
девушки современные они
listened to all these medical
наслушавшись этих всех э медицинских
preachers Yes they Well in general  they don't
проповедника Да они Ну вообще не
understand about real life I want a mother
понимают о реальной жизни я хочу маму
for my children Yes, who won't
для своих детей Да которая не будет
stuff them with some kind of I don't know ulchi,
пичкать их какими-то там не знаю ульчи
but who will be like grandparents
да а которая будут вот как бабушки
with herbs Yes, you know My husband, for example, did
травами Да знаете Мой муж например в это
n't believe in this beforehand either and my mother-in-law
тоже заранее не верил и моя свекровушка
is a candidate  medical sciences
она является кандидатом медицинских наук
and when there
и когда был вот этот
was this super situation with covid
вот была эта супер ситуация с ковидом
they all got vaccinated I Speak Don't get
они все вакцинировались я Говори Не
vaccinated please please you
вакцинируйтесь пожалуйста пожалуйста вы
don't understand what you're doing anyway
не понимаете что Вы творите всё равно
after many, many years already Yes,
спустя много-много лет уже Да уже
how many 4 years have passed and they have become
сколько 4 года прошло а они стали
just now listen to me now
только-только сейчас меня слушать сейчас
my mother is the second She says that I
моя мама вторая Она говорит то что я зря
did it in vain at first she hit herself in the chest
так поступила вначале она в грудь себя
and said that I know everything You can't
Била и говорила то что я всё знаю Ты не
imagine You're not a doctor You're
представляешь Ты же не медик Ты даже ты
not even a
не то что Врач даже не
doctor What are you  You tell me here
медик Что ты мне тут говоришь
and now in the end when all the years
а сейчас по итогу вот когда все года
have passed She says Yes I was wrong I was
прошли Она говорит Да я ошиблась Я была
wrong and my husband too She tells me the same thing
не права и муж Мой тоже Мне тоже самое
Children are not
говорит детей не
vaccinated Zhizha go destroys children And
вакцинируется Жижа го детей уничтожает А
what do you think modern school has a
как вы считаете современная школа
detrimental effect on children You teach children at home
пагубно влияет на детей вы дома Учите
my child studies at home At home And
детей мой ребнок учится дома Дома А
how old is the child Russian classical
сколько ребнку лет русская классическая
school How old is she 13 13 what grade
школа Сколько лет ей 13 13 какой класс
and sixth And what kind of Russian classical
а шестой А что за русская классическая
school
школа
is it there and they write in
там получается а пишут в
calligraphy what ink pen
каллиграфии че чернильная ручка
mathematics according to Soviet textbooks they
математика по советским учебникам они
study very slowly they are in no
очень учатся так медленно не
hurry but at the same time my  my daughter is
спешат но параллельно моя дочка учится
still studying by correspondence Well, she's holding on There's just a
ещё заочно Ну как бы держится Там просто
nerd at school holding on because now
держится зауч в школе потому что сейчас
family education is, you could say,
семейное образование оно можно сказать
equivalent to
приравнивается к
UZ, unfortunately, for now, that's it  there are
увз к сожалению сейчас пока вот есть
some like this while many still don't
такие вот пока многие ещё этого не
realize it But this is
осознают Но это
OVD Why Because they offer
овз Почему Потому что предлагают
parents an individual education plan And
родителям индивидуальный план обучения А
in our legislation there is a
у нас законодательстве
provision on education there is an individual
поз об образования там индивидуально
plan either for children with
лу либо для детей
disabilities or for special smart children And I came to
овз либо для особых умных а я пришла в
school I say that I have a child
школу я говорю то что у меня ребёнок не
she is not OVS and not particularly smart she does
овз и не особо умный ей индивидуальный
not need an individual plan and she will study to become
план не нужен и она будет учиться на
a breeder she comes to school and
заводчики она приходить в школу и
takes a test with the class
сдавать вместе с классом контрольную
nothing changes except that she
ничего не меняется Кроме того что она
studies
учится
by correspondence I understood Listen but here is such a question of
заочно понял Слушай а вот такой вопрос
starting your child to communicate with children they are
пуска свого реб сги детьми общаться они
labial  influence well these ill-mannered de
губно влияют ну эти невоспитанные де
let and in the end it turns out True she
пускаю и в итоге получается Правда она
even comes after school aggressive
даже после школы приходит агрессивная
children now swear swear fight
дети сейчас ругаются матерятся дерутся
she comes aggressive but I created
она приходит агрессивная но я создала
such an atmosphere in the house that she no longer
такую обстановку в доме то что ей уже не
wants to go for a walk or anything I say for
хочется ни гулять ничего я говорю
example Go Let's go to you there for example
например Сходи Давай тебе тамм например
3  -4 rubles You'll go eat with friends
3-4 руб Ты пойдёшь покушаешь с друзьями
there sushi rolls there you'll go to the cinema She
там суши роллы там сходишь в кино Она
says No I want to sit at home besides I
говорит Нет я хочу сидеть дома притом я
limit her in phones she has a
её ограничиваю в телефонах у неё есть
phone  only for temporary use
телефон только на временное пользование
when she goes to school to be
когда она уходит в школу чтобы быть со
in touch with me to see what
мной на связи чтобы посмотреть какие
buses there will be That's
автобусы Вот
free time Well on the phone an hour or two
и свободное время Ну в телефоне час-два
that's how you spend
этото бывает как вы проводите
Sunday on Sunday we spend
воскресенье в воскресенье мы проводим
together with the family or watch movies or my
вместе с семьёй либо смотрим фильмы либо
daughter watches there  my own little
дочка смот там свои какие-нибудь там
TV series or movies before all this
сериальчики фильмы раньше до этого всего
I controlled her
я её контролировала
tastes What does she watch Well, so that she
по вкусу Да что она смотрит Ну чтобы она
doesn't watch something
не смотрела что-нибудь такое
destructive or anything like that, I don't
деструктивное что-нибудь такое не я имею
mean you go to some
в виду вы там ходите на какие-то в
church or something  that or
церковь какую-то или
that I don't believe in the
что я не верю в
church they too My mother
церковь они тоже У меня мама в своё
was an Old Church member at one time and I
время была Старо церкви и я в своё время
also went to church a lot at one time But when
тоже очень ходила много церковь Но когда
I went to church why did I often
я при хола в церковь почему это часто
cry a lot And when I went to
очень плакала А когда я пошла на
Confession I cried 4  hours until my
Исповедь я плакала 4 часа пока моя
Confession came I didn't understand Why
Исповедь не пришла Я не понимала Почему
I thought probably to such an extent about
я думала наверное до такой степени о
sinful and my husband turns out that my husband is a
грешна а муж оказывается что мой муж
journalist journalist And how much do
журналист журналист А сколько сейчас
journalists
журналисты
earn now Well, decently enough for a family for
зарабатывают Ну прилично на семью
the five of us enough I
хватает на нас пятерых хватает
understood you and your husband relate to  this war
понял относите с мужем к этой войне
that is going on
которая идт
now is very bad very negative And
сейчас очень плохо очень негативно А
why is this
почему это
my husband he is partly
во у меня муж он на часть
Ukrainian And why did this war start Do
украинец А почему эта война началась Как
you
вы
think this war started because
думаете эта война началась от того то
people do not have enough power people want to
что людям не хватает власти люди хотят
leave behind history what kind of
оставить за собой историю какие именно
people are the highest the highest  people are
люди высшие высшие люди
simple for us I for example don't need her Well
простые нам мне например она не нужна Ну
at least name one person this is from these
хоть одного человека назви это из этих
higher people I won't I won't
высших людей не буду не буду себя
drive myself into such spaces that I do
вгонять в такие просторы которые мне
n't need them now you yourself will understand everything
сейчас они не нужны ты сам всё поймёт
understood understood And as for children it turns out Where
понял понял А по детям получается Куда
Children want to go After school I
Дети хотят поступать После школы я
I say the most important thing is not alcoholism or
говорю самое главное не алкоголизм не
drug addiction or something like that Shotokan wherever you want I
наркомания не то-то сётокан куда хочешь
say Where your soul
говорю Куда твоя душа
strives try yourself in all directions I say
стремится пробуй себя во всех говорю
sports Try this
направлениях спорт Попробуй этот
Try that dancing all sorts Try
Попробуй тот танцы всякое Попробуй
Say And what if my daughter goes to
Говори А а если дочка пойдёт чтобы
be a doctor like her
Медиком быть как
mother-in-law Well, let it be but I  for
тёща Хорошо пусть будет но я же для
this and I exist as a mother who has a
этого и Существую как мама которая с
different experience which will not direct why you
другим опытом которые е направит почему
need to be a doctor you can be earlier
Медиком нужно быть можно быть раньше
What kind of doctors were they were
Какие доктора были они были
multidisciplinary and now there are many
многопрофильные а сейчас много
narrow-profile yes And what in the end Well yes
узкопрофильных да И что в итоге Ну да
you come and say something like  my doctor
приходишь говоришь типа доктор у меня
look at the cardiogram he says I don't
Посмотрите кардиограмму он говорит Не
know I'm a urologist yes
знаю я уролог да
But
А
before everything could be cured But now
раньше можно было всё вылечить А сейчас
what Yes so much knowledge before there were
что Да столько знаний на раньше были
people doctors who treated and now
люди лекари которые лечили а сейчас
doctors who lie lie Yes doctor word
врачи которые врут врут Да врач слово
lie yes
врать да
and doctors they
а лекари они
understood multidisciplinary
разбирались в многопрофильных
things what  you about yourself will tell your
вещах что вы про себя ра расскажете своё
opinion about this world I will say Yes the thing is it is
мнение об этом мире я скажу Да дело в
nice to meet a girl
том что приятно встретить такую девушку
like you I am from the Ancient khars family Well,
как вы я из Древнего харс рода Ну вот у
my father is Mari and in our family the
меня ж отец мариец и у нас по роду
healers passed down the methods We also collect I
знахарки методики Мы тоже собираем
don't know how here  you have Yes we also dry
не знаю как вот у вас Да мы ещё сушим
birch ones these
берёзовые вот эти
when
когда
birch ones for what and from them very
берёзовые для чего и от них очень
good tea When to drink it relaxes it
хороший чай Когда пить он релаксу ет
soothes complete calm Yes here
успокаивает полное успокоение Да вот
if we take two
если берём две чайных
teaspoons of dried Yes pour
ложки сушеных Да заливаем
in the fifth like this Ida you can also add either
в пятом так Ида ещё можно добавить либо
mint or lemon balm or mint  or Melissa
мяту либо мелиссу либо мяту либо мелиссу
Tano you collect
Тано вы собираете
here we collect too yes I have well now I
вот собираем тоже да у меня ну сейчас не
can't show it she is on another floor Yes
могу показать она в на другом этаже Да
there are three cans collected it's simple
есть три банки собрано это просто вот у
my mom also collects and imagine
меня мама тоже собирает и представляете
with her hands And is there such a way to collect
руками А есть такой способ чтобы собрать
faster yes yes Yes faster look
быстрее есть есть Да быстрее смотрите
there is such a special device
есть такое э специальный приборчик
Yes but they specifically
делается Да но и о нём специально
keep silent about it we uh made a program about it
умалчивают мы ээ делали передачу об этом
yes on youtube how people can collect Yes
да в юбе как людям можно собирать Да
to treat themselves  YouTube banned us, it
чтобы лечиться нам YouTube забанил это
hides information everywhere, it's just
всюду скрывает информация берётся просто
a battery,
батарейка
uh, a wire, yes, it goes, the current goes through
ээ проводок такой да идёт Ток по
the battery, it gets electrified and attracts
батарейке он электризуется и притягивает
it, it just builds up on this wire,
это прямо нарастает на этой проволочки
so you turn off the button, that is, you
так отключаешь кнопочку То есть ты
press, for how long does it
нажимаешь В течение какого времени она
attract, how much, just like that,
притягивается сколько прямо вот так вот
we press, turn it on and  bring here
мы нажимаешь Включаешь и подносишь вот
KK to these pine things listen My
КК этим сосновым штукам слушайте У меня
dad is an Energy drinker you can do this Yes with
папа Энергетик можно это сделать Да
your own hands Yes he can yes tell him so that the
своими руками Да он может да скажете ему
battery wire so that the
чтобы батарейка провод чтобы
electric field
электрическое поле электростатика
attracts electrostatics and everything it attracts
притягивает и всё она притягивает
electrostatics Yes yes I did I
электростатики Да да я делал я вам
will show you my pine tree now Here is my mom
сейчас покажу свою сосну Вот моя мама
doing  you know what it mixes with honey
делает знаете с чем с мёдом смешивает
you mix it with honey we have it separately we have the
вы смешиваете с мёдом мы отдельно у нас
thing is that we have  we have
Дело в том что у нас есть у нас есть
our own personal apiary you buy honey or
своя личная пасека вы покупаете мёд или
we also have our own friends beekeepers and we have our
у нас тоже свои друзья пасечники а у нас
own apiary and we special We have 18
своя пасека и мы спе У нас есть 18
varieties of honey 18 varieties of different honey
сортов мёда 18 сортов мёда разных это
what are these linden ones there are yes specially then
какие это липовые там есть да специально
look we have When for
значит смотрите у нас есть Когда
example acacias bloom  Yes, we
например цветут акации Да мы
go out m near acacias if
выезжаем м возле акаций если цветёт
buckwheat is blooming We are near buckwheat Yes, if they are blooming
гречка Мы возле гречки Да если цветут
there is dandelion honey here we have e
есть одуванчиковый мёд вот у нас есть э
When dandelions are blooming there are whole fields of
Когда цветут Одуванчики есть целые поля
dandelion like this Yes, it is so
одуванчиковый такие Да вот он настолько
yellow, you know, just like
жёлтый прямо знаете вот прямо как
Radiant, it is so useful Yes,
Лучезарный он настолько полезный Да вот
it is very rare  dandelion honey, well, let's
очень редкий это одуванчиковый мёд вот
say I don't know if it's
есть ещё ну скажем не знаю ли у вас это
common here in Ukraine, uh,
распространено у нас тут в Украине ээ
they get honey from
добывают ээ мёд из с
ferns, we've heard of that once, so
папоротника слышали такое когда-то так
never. And even from Vanchik, I've
вот никогда И даже из-за Ванчик никогда
never heard of it, and from ferns, especially
не слышала а из папоротника тем боле вот
ferns.  Yes, we have  fern
папоротника Да у нас есть папоротниковые
forests that is in the forests there are a lot of
леса то есть в лесах очень много
thickets of ferns and there when you
зарослей папоротников и там когда вот Вы
look at the folders on the lower side there are
посмотрите папок на Нижней стороне там
such droplets that gather this is specially
такие капельки собираются это специально
blooms once they say that on
цветёт один раз вот говорят то что на
Kupala night Kupala night Yes that's
купаль ночь купаль ночь Да так вот
exactly it 3 days before Kupala night and 3
именно да 3 дня до купальский ночи и 3
days after Kupala these 6 days
дня после купальский вот эти 6 дней
we take the members to the forests and they collect
мы вывозим чл в леса и они собирают
exactly the fern MD there such a
именно папоротник МД там такие лый
business this is such logistics this is here and there
бизнес это такая логистика это туда сюда
Well this is health you understand this is health this is
Ну это здоровье понимаете это здоровье
health this is health our ancestors
это здоровье это здоровье наши предки
did it this way they did not go to the
так и делали они же они не ходили в
supermarket  bought honey True, they,
супермаркет покупали мёд Правда они вот
you know, the most interesting thing is that when
самое интересно знаете что вот когда у
I was pregnant and had terrible atitis
меня была беременность и был жуткий атит
and nit And in general, I couldn't bend over. My VS
и нит И вообще ВС я нагнуться не могла
hurt. You know, what helped me was
ВС у меня болела знаете что мне помогло
this, this, what's it called,
вот это вот этот как называется-то
alcohol and something bee-based  What
спирт и что-то пчелиное Как
is the name of the
называется
bee bread not bee bread propolis propolis
перга не перга прополис прополис
propolis I am propolis Nothing helped me anymore
прополис я прополис Мне уже ничего не
I started mixing propolis with
помогало я стала прополис смешивать с
water dilute and dripping it into my nose Yeah
водой разбавлять и капать себе в нос Угу
And it didn't help me either  so it saved then pressed the
И меня это так спасло потом прижат
first presidential ENT there is 5000
первую президентскую лору там 5000 стоит
there once to run and for an examination She
там один раз прибежать да на осмотр Она
says I would you says udu I say In the
говорит я бы тебя говорит уду я говорю В
sense She says you have such polyps I
смысле Она говорит у тебя такие полипы Я
say otherwise the doctor would look at me last year did
говорю а то чтобы меня врач в том году
not find anything in you
смотрел Ничего не обнаружила у тебя
says polyp for several years and this this this
говорит полипом несколько лет и вот это
this tincture saved me How do
вот вот это вот настойка меня спасла Как
you feel many people ridicule me I
вы относитесь многие высмеивают счита я
practice this
вот практикую это
urine therapy this is urine therapy what
уринотерапия это уринотерапия что это
is it uh when urine uh they are treated with urine
такое э когда мочу э лечатся мочой
especially there uh small children there there up
особенно там ээ маленьких детей там там
to 14 years old there are up to 8 you know  if
до 14 лет есть до 8ми знаете если
I take it internally I have never
принять внутрь себя я никогда не
tried it I can't but if I take
пробовала не смогу вот а если принять
a bath after children who don't watch
ванну после детишек которые не следят Да
their urination then why
за своим мочеиспусканием то почему бы и
not they tried it on the skin they say it has a
нет пробовали оно на кожу говорят влияет
very good effect in the bath Yes I tried it but
очень хорошо в ванну Да пробовала но
Poti children yes yes yes and How does it feel
Поти детишек да дада да и Как ощущение
you can't even see it maybe they
её даже не видно может быть они там
did something there or maybe they didn't even
что-то сделали А может быть даже не
do it but I think at least once I managed to
сделали но думаю хотя бы раз мне удалось
do it take a bath they say
это сделать принять это ванну говорят
that they have enzymes Yes in the nursery
что у них вот у ферменты Да в детской ч
they  kill all the bad microbes and from the
они убивают всех микробов плохих да и с
skin Yes, parasitic ones are killed from the skin
кожи Да с кожи убивается
We have so many parasites
паразитарные у нас столько паразитов то
that you can't get rid of them with just urine and
что там одной мочой не отделаешься а кал
what kind of feces did they use Well, their own in treatment
использовали какой кал Ну свой в лечени
or not there ma and what else do they use feces
или нет там ма а что ещё кал используют
really And what And what do they do with  Kalam ointments
правда А что А что делают с Калам мази
from feces It seems to me that feces is a super
из кала Мне кажется кала - это супер
processed product that
переработанный продукт который уже
simply cannot be flushed down the toilet in any way
просто кроме как смыть в унитаз никак
and even the Earth will not accept it because,
нельзя и даже Земля его не примет потому
well, damn, that's exactly how to
что ну блин так вот именно э калом
burn out e with feces if Look, we use chemicals,
выжигать если Смотри Е употребляем хими
look, I'll tell you how Former
смотрите я вам скажу как Бывший
employee  morgue I will tell you that
сотрудник морга я вам скажу то что
now even bodies do not decompose for
сейчас даже тела они не разлагаются в
15 years yes because we
течение 15 лет да потому что мы
eat all kinds of food that we As a
употребляем всякую пищу которая нас В
result, we can say E we are covered, we can
итоге можно сказать Э мы покрыты можно
say, with formalin I will explain why e
сказать формалином я объясню почему э
Where feces are used The thing is that
Где используется кал Дело в том что
look We have a very  many invisible
смотрите У нас очень много невидимых
parasites Yes on the skin And so on
паразитов Да на коже И так дальше вот
these small ones that are parasites in feces
этих мелких которые паразитов в кале
well roundworms so no so look not
хорошо аскариды так нет так смотри не
just feces Yes feces uh it
как раз именно кал Да кал ээ там
contains  there are a lot of reactive
содержится очень много реактивных
substances that kill everything and therefore
веществ которые убивают всё да и поэтому
if you make lubricants Yes, they
если делаете смазки Да вот они
kill you know I am of course for traditional
убивают знаете я конечно за народную
medicine but feces are when through Shchur
медицину но кал - это когда через Щур
through Shchur so also for example people
через Щур так также например люди
who worked in the garden if they
которые работали в огороде если они
for example worked with manure specifically in
например работали с навозом именно в
manure very  there were many different
навозе очень много находилось всяких
larvae of all sorts of other parasites It
личинок всяких других паразитов
turns out They don't die,
получается Они кали не умирают они
on the contrary, there are more like there, even
наоборот там больше как бы там они даже
if they break nests, it turns out to be the most
если гнёзда бьют получается самая
favorable environment, well, well,
благоприятная среда хорошо а так ну
maybe a little bit of an intimate question, yes,
может немножко такой интимный вопрос да
uh, let's say there is uh, instead of modern
ээ скажем есть ээ вместо современной
cosmetics, that I don't see you
косметики что я вас не вижу
yes instead of modern cosmetics our
да вместо современной косметики наши
ancestors used masks Yeah That's
предки использовали маски Угу Вот потому
because men's it has very
что мужская она обладает очень
vital microelements so because
живильна микроэлементами так потому что
well Maybe if it is used for example
ну Возможно если её например используют
in a complete lipstick yes At least it is
в окупной помаде да По крайней мере там
written there that in each complete
так написано то что в каждой купно
lipstick there is a
помаде находится
custom and then it's up to the person  how is he
обычая вот а дальше дело человека как он
like
как
this Ugu in general here's five And you haven't
этому Угу вообще вот пя А вы не про не
tried masks like I don't And you've
пробовали маски типа Я нет А вы
tried Well I don't need it I'm a man like
пробовали Ну мне не надо я мужчина типа
I don't  And why wait now such a
я не А почему подождите сейчас такое
time that
время то что
you know that a woman that a man already
знаете что женщина что мужчина уже
watch their face no not the point that
следят своим лицом не не дело в том что
look eh male it acts
смотрите э мужская она действует
positively on a woman so
позитивно на женщину так
why male I read I read these A
пому мужская Я читал Я читал эти А
well Who wrote Well di which healers
хорошо Кто написал Ну ди которые знахари
who practice ё  research what is
которые практикуют ё исследование как
the name not scientists scientists are keeping quiet
зовут не не учёные учёные замалчивают
This is good What is the name of this healer
Это хорошо Как зовут этого знахаря
German
Герман
Sterligov German
Стерлигов Герман
Sterli who lives just
стерли который живёт как раз таки
near the
недалеко от
Moscow region billionaire Yes do you believe him
Подмосковья миллиардер Да вы ему верите
Yes he achieved everything himself he knows how he
Да он всего добился сам он умеет он
places he does he is treated also And what
помести делает он лечится также А что
if a person something-  then he achieved, for example,
если человек чего-то добился например
that's how fate laid it out, it
вот Судьба так рас положила то
turns out that he can be trusted. Well,
получается то что ему можно верить Ну он
look, he lives, he lives according to the family
смотрите он живёт он живёт по родовому
way of life, he lives without any electricity, but that
укладу живёт без электрики всякой но это
doesn't mean that he is completely right. Well, I
же не значит что он полноценно прав Ну я
think he has a place to be, here we are.
думаю он имеет место быть вот нам
Look, we are with  you live differently Yes,
Посмотрите мы с вами живём по-другому Да
but we also have our own charter and we live according to our
но у нас тоже свой устав и мы живём по
own schedule, but this does not mean
своему раскладу но это не говорит о том
that you and I are wrong and that we are not
что мы с вами не правы и то что нас не
worth listening
стоит слушать
and what do you think How many wives should a
а как вы считаете Сколько жён должно
man have one The most beloved the dearest
мужчины одна Самая любимая самая родная
the only And how many husbands
самая единственная А сколько мужей
should a
должно быть у
woman have husbands a woman And what do you think I
женщины мужей у женщины А как вы думаете
don't know How don't you know why don't you know
не знаю Как не знаете почему не знаете
Well your version is good And how many would you
Ну ваша версия хорошо А сколько бы вы
like  yourself
хотели себе
zh three and why
жн три а почему
one washes the second cooks the third
одна стирает вторая готовит третья
puts to bed which one washes cooks now there
укладывает какой стирает готовит сейчас
are already washing
уже есть стиральные
machines this is not a problem at all
машины это уже вообще не проблема
look Vasya has deep stains
смотрите есть у Васе глубокие пятна
that the washing machine will not wash out will
которые стиральная машина не отстирается
wash off good Pashka media with your hands will you
отрут хорошие Пашки СМИ руками вы будете
use your
пользоваться
hands no arrives rush with your hands third
руками нет приезжает мчи руками третье
wife  a man can be a
жен мужчина может это нам
worker for us money is needed You would you
работник деньги нуно Вы вы бы вообще бы
then be able to provide for yourself and live your whole life
тогда могли бы всю свою жизнь сами себе
Without a wife as if and there
обеспечить и жить Без жены как бы и там
Bought and here bought and
Купил и тут купил и
there there is one there is one nuance if you
там есть один есть один нюанс если так
think about it like that what
соображать какой
nuance as if and Reproduction of the race
нюанс как бы и Воспроизводство рода
myself So far it doesn't
самому Пока не
work Well you can buy
получается Хорошо можно купить
Reproduction can also be bought now
Воспроизводство тоже можно купить сейчас
there are these
бывают вот эти
Oh, I'm sorry now there are women
вот Ой прости сейчас бывают женщины
who get money for this Yes
которые за это деньги получают Да
who reproduce your kind If you are
которые воспроизводят ваш род Если Вы
almost If you are almost infertile or
почти Если Вы почти бесплодные либо у
you don't have a uterus or a
вас не имеется матки либо
woman Well, look
женщины Ну смотри получается почему
it turns out why exactly three one - it's well somehow boring yes Why is it boring and more TH simply physically there is not enough time and it is impossible in one as if to observe everything it is impossible For example, one Well one may have a headache at this moment but you don't may have a headache Well when my head hurts I don't want anything ok if you have three wives then let your wife have three men too Why Well because your head may hurt too you have prostatitis then you don't earn money then what else ours our ancestors how did they live for example there was a prince he had more than one wife he had many concubines prince Vladimir had 800 concubines in Vyshgorod And who is Vladimir the one who baptized the sun who yes And what do you know about him Well I know he baptized Rus' he was a good guy but history was rewritten Peres everything was given Or maybe they made it up yes about alternative history by the way Tell me yes I'm interested I won't You don't tell me much of this I read I read Fomenko I read about this  Fomenko history what did you
Об этом я читал Фоменко историю ты что
read I read all sorts of different sources
читала я всякие разные разные источники
tried and understood Well
читала пробовала и понима Ну
I tried to come to an understanding what is
пыталась дойти до понимания что мне
closer to me what is not closer to me in my
ближе что мне не ближе по
gut as you know the ancient city of Arkaim
нутру как ты знаешь древний город Аркаим
Arkaim
Аркаим
Arkaim is somewhere in the direction of Africa in
Аркаим это где-то в стороне Африки в
Siberia in Siberia Siberia No no
Сибири в Сибири Сибири Нет не
arch and what
арка и что там
is there Well, you have to see it it was
находится Ну это надо посмотреть он был
in the form of a circle
в форме Круга
And
А как ты считаешь
how many millennia do you think Russians have existed
сколько тысячелетий существуют русские
everything and the
всё и
character Blin broke off when she said about
персонаж Блин когда она сказала за
the dryer It was a
сушилку Это был
shkd comment letter nay Telegram right now
шкд комент пись най Telegram прям зараз
axis and
ось а
pok ts very and very  important YouTube is busy
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through scarg or in your ban and very
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show to people sometimes I do not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we Mali operational links
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
are written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegram okrim videos also interesting and
телеграми окрим вдео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we  I'm sorry about
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
your constant operational connection,
постийний оперативный звязок
I'll show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava Ukraine write
YouTube Слава украини пиши
with
с